[{"title":"PMP","question":"What does the acronym PMP stand for?","answer":"Project Management Professional","reference":"http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Project_Management_Professional","viewed":0,"right":0,"wrong":0},{"title":"Performance Domains","question":"What are the 6 performance domains?","answer":"<ul><li>Initiating the project</li><li>Planning the project</li><li>Executing the project</li><li>Monitoring and Controlling the Project</li><li>Closing the Project</li><li>Professional and Social Responsibility</li></ul>","reference":"http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Project_Management_Professional","viewed":0,"right":0,"wrong":0},{"title":"Project lifecycle process groups","question":"What are the 5 project lifecycle process groups?","answer":"<ul><li>Initiating</li><li>Planning or design</li><li>Executing or production</li><li>Monitoring and Controlling</li><li>Closing or completion</li></ul>","reference":"http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Project_Management_Professional","viewed":0,"right":0,"wrong":0},{"title":"Knowledge areas","question":"What are the 9 knowledge areas for project management?","answer":"<ol> <li>Project Integration Management</li> <li>Project Scope Management</li> <li>Project Time Management</li> <li>Project Cost Management</li> <li>Project Quality Management</li> <li>Project Human Resource Management</li> <li>Project Communications Management</li> <li>Project Risk Management</li> <li>Project Procurement Management</li> </ol>","reference":"http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Project_Management_Professional","viewed":0,"right":0,"wrong":0},{"title":"Henry Gannt","question":"Who was Henry Gannt","answer":"The father of planning and control techniques, who is famous for his use of the Gantt chart as a project management tool.","reference":"http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Project_management","viewed":0,"right":0,"wrong":0},{"title":"Henri Fayol","question":"Who was Henri Fayol","answer":" Created the 5 management functions which form the foundation of the body of knowledge associated with project and program management.","reference":"http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Project_management","viewed":0,"right":0,"wrong":0},{"title":"IMPA","question":"What does the acronym IMPA stand for?","answer":"The International Project Management Association (IPMA) was founded in Europe in 1967","reference":"http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Project_management","viewed":0,"right":0,"wrong":0},{"title":"PMI","question":"What does the acronym PMI stand for?","answer":"In 1969, the Project Management Institute (PMI) was formed in the USA","reference":"http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Project_management","viewed":0,"right":0,"wrong":0},{"title":"CCPM","question":"What is critical chain project management?","answer":"Critical Chain Project Management (CCPM) is a method of planning and managing projects that puts more emphasis on the resources (physical and human) needed in order to execute project tasks. Regardless of project type, the project plan should undergo Resource Leveling, and the longest sequence of resource-constrained tasks should be identified as the critical chain.","reference":"http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Project_management","viewed":0,"right":0,"wrong":0},{"title":"PERT","question":"Describe Program Evaluation and Review Technique","answer":"The Program (or Project) Evaluation and Review Technique, commonly abbreviated PERT, is a model for project management designed to analyze and represent the tasks involved in completing a given project. It is commonly used in conjunction with the critical path method or CPM. It is more of an event-oriented technique rather than start- and completion-oriented, and is used more in projects where time, rather than cost, is the major factor. It is applied to very large-scale, one-time, complex, non-routine infrastructure and Research and Development projects.","reference":"http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PERT","viewed":0,"right":0,"wrong":0},{"title":"Theory of Constraints","question":"What are the 5 focusing steps of the Theory of Constraints","answer":"<ol> <li>Identify the constraint (the resource or policy that prevents the organization from obtaining more of the goal)</li> <li>Decide how to exploit the constraint (make sure the constraint's time is not wasted doing things that it should not do)</li> <li>Subordinate all other processes to above decision (align the whole system or organization to support the decision made above)</li> <li>Elevate the constraint (if required or possible, permanently increase capacity of the constraint; \"buy more\")</li> <li>If, as a result of these steps, the constraint has moved, return to Step 1. Don't let <a href=\"/wiki/Social_inertia\" title=\"Social inertia\">inertia</a> become the constraint.</li> </ol>","reference":"http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Theory_of_Constraints","viewed":0,"right":0,"wrong":0},{"title":"ISO 15504 or SPICE","question":"Software Process Improvement Capability Determination","answer":"ISO 15504, also known as Software Process Improvement Capability Determination (SPICE), is a \"framework for the assessment of software processes\". This standard is aimed at setting out a clear model for process comparison. SPICE is used much like CMMI. It models processes to manage, control, guide and monitor software development. This model is then used to measure what a development organization or project team actually does during software development. This information is analyzed to identify weaknesses and drive improvement. It also identifies strengths that can be continued or integrated into common practice for that organization or team.","reference":"http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_Development_Life_Cycle","viewed":0,"right":0,"wrong":0},{"title":"Scrum","question":"What is Scrum?","answer":"Scrum is an iterative, incremental framework for project management and agile software development. The word is not an acronym. <ol><li>the <b>ScrumMaster</b>, who maintains the processes (typically in lieu of a project manager)</li><li>the <b>Product Owner</b>, who represents the stakeholders and the business</li><li>the <b>Team</b>, a cross-functional group of about 7 people who do the actual analysis, design, implementation, testing, etc.</li></ol>","reference":"http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SCRUM","viewed":0,"right":0,"wrong":0},{"title":"Chickens and Pigs","question":"Who are the chickens and pigs?","answer":"In Scrum, a chicken is not part of the process, they are the ones for whom the software is being built. A pig is the one with \"their bacon on the line.\"","reference":"http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Chicken_and_the_Pig","viewed":0,"right":0,"wrong":0},{"title":"Kanban","question":"What is a kanban system?","answer":"Based on the toyota model, treats the process like a supermarket.","reference":"http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kanban","viewed":0,"right":0,"wrong":0},{"title":"Burn-down","question":"What is a burn-down chart?","answer":"The sprint burn down chart is a publicly displayed chart showing remaining work in the sprint backlog. Updated every day, it gives a simple view of the sprint progress. It also provides quick visualizations for reference. There are also other types of burndown, for example the Release Burndown Chart that shows the amount of work left to complete the target commitment for a Product Release (normally spanning through multiple iterations) and the Alternative Release Burndown Chart[14], which basically does the same, but clearly shows scope changes to Release Content, by resetting the baseline.","reference":"http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SCRUM","viewed":0,"right":0,"wrong":0},{"title":"Scrum Meetings","question":"What are the 3 questions each team member must answer daily?","answer":"<ul> <li>What have you done since yesterday?</li> <li>What are you planning to do today?</li> <li>Do you have any problems preventing you from accomplishing your goal? (It is the role of the ScrumMaster to facilitate resolution of these impediments. Typically this should occur outside the context of the Daily Scrum so that it may stay under 15 minutes.)</li> </ul>","reference":"http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SCRUM","viewed":0,"right":0,"wrong":0},{"title":"DSDM","question":"What is DSDM","answer":"Dynamic Systems Development Method (DSDM) is a software development methodology originally based upon the Rapid Application Development methodology. DSDM is an iterative and incremental approach that emphasizes continuous user involvement. It is a forerunner/related to Scrum. It has a post-delivery phase that is useful for engaging the customer and review.","reference":"http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DSDM","viewed":0,"right":0,"wrong":0},{"title":"ROC","question":"What is a Receiver operating characteristic","answer":"In signal detection theory, a receiver operating characteristic (ROC), or simply ROC curve, is a graphical plot of the sensitivity, or true positives, vs. (1 âˆ’ specificity), or false positives, for a binary classifier system as its discrimination threshold is varied.","reference":"http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Receiver_operating_characteristic","viewed":0,"right":0,"wrong":0},{"title":"V-Model","question":"What is V-Model (software development)?","answer":"Verification and Validation.  The V-Model demonstrates the relationships between each phase of the development life cycle and its associated phase of testing. The horizontal and vertical axes represents time or project completeness (left-to-right) and level of abstraction (coarsest-grain abstraction uppermost), respectively. These include Requirement Analysis, System Design, Architecture Design, and Module Design, followed by Unit Testing, Integration Testing, System Testing, and Acceptance Testing.","reference":"http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/V-Model_(software_development)","viewed":0,"right":0,"wrong":0},{"title":"Robert Burns","question":"Quote \"To A Mouse\" November 1785","answer":"But Mousie, thou are no thy-lane,  In proving foresight may be vain:  The best laid schemes o' Mice an' Men,  Gang aft agley,  An' lea'e us nought but grief an' pain,  For promis'd joy!","reference":"http://www.electricscotland.com/burns/mouse.html","viewed":0,"right":0,"wrong":0}]